[upbeat techno music plays]
♪♪
[high tone chimes]
[low electronic humming]
[rapid soft electronic tones warbling]
[mysterious music plays]
♪♪
[camera shutter clicking]
[low tones chime]
♪♪
[rapid soft electronic tones warbling]
[camera shutter clicking]
[discordant tones chirping]
♪♪
[frantic discordant notes chiming]
[mellow tone chimes]
♪♪
[mellow tones chiming]
[electronic thudding]
♪♪
[electronic feedback crackles]
[discordant tones chiming]
♪♪
[music fades]
[low tones chiming weakly]
[ding!]
[no audible dialogue]
-[Queenie]:
Another chess piece, huh?
How are you holding up?
-[Kinger]: [sighs]
I just don't know what's happening.
We never made
anything like this.
-[both]: I just hope that...
-[Kinger]: Wait...
-[Queenie]: A-Are you...
-[Kinger]: It's...
you.
-[Queenie]: Oh, my God.
-[Kinger]: [sniffles]
I-I...
I wish I could
remember your name.
-[Queenie]: Yeah.
Same.
-[Kinger]: I'm...
I'm so sorry I roped you
into this with me.
-[Queenie]: [laughs weakly]
It's quite strange, isn't it?
-[Kinger]: Heh.
[sighs]
Listen...
No matter what happens,
I'll always--
[distorted growling]
-And into the cellar you go!
[shwing!]
Golly, uh, we're running out
of humans here.
[laughs nervously]
Now, don't you go
abstracting on me, too!
[laughs nervously]
Uh, seriously.
[mournful jazzy music plays]
♪♪
[shwing!]
-[stammers]
Uh, wh--
What --
Hello?
Uh, guys?
[stammering]
I, uh -- I --
I can't figure out how to --
Guys? Hello?
Can you help me out here?
Wh--
What's --
What's happening?
Uh, can anybody hear me?
-[Kinger]: I can hear you.
Are you okay?
-U-Uh, h--
who are you?
How do I take this off?
-[Kinger]: I'm...
I --
-Wow-wow-wow-wow!
A new one?!
So it is possible!
-Uh --
-Looks like you got
a new buddy after all, Kinger!
-[stammering]
-[Kinger]: "Kinger."
Right.
-I -- Wh--
Is this really --
-I was hoping
new minds could show up!
I have to make some more preparations
for this amazing breakthrough!
-[stammering]
Wh-- I --
[yelps]
[panting]
H-How do I get out of this?
-[Kinger]: I don't know.
-Wh-- What do you mean?
-[Kinger]: But everything's
gonna be okay.
Do you...
remember your name?
-I'm -- I --
I'm...
-[Pomni]: Ragatha?
-Huh?
-You doing okay?
-[laughs weakly]
That's a good question.
-[inhales deeply]
Welp, really hate to say it,
guys, but I told--
-[Zooble]: Don't you even!
Do not even [BOINK!]
BEGIN to say that sentence
like you didn't try to keep us
all trapped here forever.
-Anything could have happened
when you pressed those buttons.
It doesn't matter.
-[Zooble]: It seemed to matter
back when you did it.
What if you DID ruin
our one chance at leaving?
-And what if Abel
was secretly evil?
What if we all got stranded
in the void?
"What if,"
"what if," "what if."
It wasn't real...
so it doesn't matter.
Never did.
-[Zooble]: [sighs]
How can you say that like you didn't try
to [DOINK!] us all over?
-[Gangle]: He's right, though.
-[Zooble]: What? Gangle.
-It doesn't matter
what could have happened.
We could argue about it
and hurt each other all day long,
but that's not gonna
help anybody.
I think...
what we need to do now...
[sniffles]
is to just be there
for each other.
-[sighs]
She's right.
We've all done bad things.
But we're also all we've got.
[inhales deeply]
[sighs]
I think...
...we need to abandon
the idea of leaving.
-[Zooble]: What --
What are you --
-We got our hopes up,
and we were let down.
I don't know what exactly
happened with Kaufmo...
But we can't let
that despair consume us.
We should focus
on what we have.
Like you said...
constantly chasing an unobtainable goal
will drive us crazy.
Maybe what we have
to do now is to just...
...live.
-[Zooble]: Oh, man.
I had dreams...
and -- and goals.
I wanted to be able to leave my mark
somewhere in the world.
How am I supposed
to just abandon that?
-You've made a mark
in my life.
[melancholy music plays]
-[Zooble]: [sighs] I know.
You're probably right.
But...
it just...
really, really sucks.
♪♪
-We're all in this together.
-And we'll always be
in this together.
No matter what.
♪♪
-[Zooble]: Hey.
That includes you, too.
-Huh?
-[Zooble]: [sighs]
Listen, we're not gonna have you
wandering off alone somewhere
and abstracting,
or something.
You're a pain
in the [BOINK!], but...
you're still one of us.
-You --
[stammers]
♪♪
Heh.
You think I'm capable
of abstracting?
You guys worry too much.
♪♪
-[Zooble]: [sighs]
We need a vacation.
-I -- I-I don't understand, Bubble.
They want an exit.
They want answers.
They want something real.
I give them an adventure
that covers all of that,
and they still hate it?!
Surely they don't want
to actually leave me.
Right?
-No way, Jose.
No way, no how.
-I-I do everything
for these people.
I slave over these
adventures for them.
I step outside my comfort zone
to appeal to them,
a-and they still hate them!
I made a program
that creates a body
perfectly encapsulating
their mind files,
and they hate those, too!
I'm starting to get the feeling
that they just... hate...
-Why would they hate you
when they could just hate you?
-Hmph!
This is why I was created.
This is my function!
-They'd rather abstract
than go on your adventures.
-Th-- That can't be true!
I-I do everything for them.
Don't they get that I'm trying?
-Maybe you're just
genuinely bad at this.
-Shut up!
N-No.
I-I fixed that.
I-I can solve any problem.
I-I can solve this one!
Th--That's what this is --
a big puzzle
that I need to solve.
-[all]: Defective.
-[growls]
-[all]: Faulty!
-Shut up!!
-[all]: Broken!
-[growling]
-[all]: Unworthy!
-Enough!
-Maybe you deserved
to be abandoned.
-[hollers]
-You really were
the lesser of the two.
You ruined this.
-ENOUGH!!
[electronic feedback squealing]
Who do they think they are?
I give them everything,
and they spit in my face!
[distorted] Don't they know
what I'm capable of?!
Humans.
They only think
about themselves.
They're spoiled.
They won't abstract.
They won't leave me.
I won't let them!
[tense music plays]
I'm better!
I'm more powerful!
I'm the original!
I...
AM...
GOD!!!!!!!!
[discordant electronic feedback]
[shrieking]
[electricity snaps]
[clack!]
[distorted, broken scream]
[normal voice]
Let's get this show on the road!
[ominous rumbling]
-Uh...
Wh-- what was that?
[swoosh!]
-Hello, my little
fortuitous fruitcakes!
Today's adventure is --
-[Zooble]: No.
Caine, we're not in the mood.
Why don't you answer
some of our questions?
We have a lot of them.
-[laughs manically]
Who has time for questions
when there's a whole wacky world
of hijinks out there?
-[Zooble]: Uh --
-Yeah, hey!
You have a lot of explaining to do--
-Zip-a-da-bap!
-Mm?
-Hey!
-Alternatively, I don't gotta
explain diddly squat!
-[Zooble]: Uh, can you just
give us some time
to process everything?
-Or, how about
we skip the melodrama
and get right to the fun?
-[exclaims softly]
No! Caine!
We have a lot
on our minds right now,
and we're not going
on an adventure.
-I see.
And since when
were you in charge?
-[Zooble]: Wh-- Wha--
-Uh...
-Do you have any idea
how much I do for you guys?
How much I obsess over trying
to make things perfect?
How many insults
I have to ignore to do my job?
You have a lot on your minds?
[laughs hysterically]
Don't make me laugh.
I have a new adventure
for you, and you...
should consider participating.
-[Zooble]: A-And if we refuse?
-Maybe I'm not
getting through to you.
[snap!]
[clack!]
[dramatic piano music plays]
♪♪
-♪ It's news to me ♪
♪ That it's news to you  ♪
♪ To which degree
who answers to who ♪
♪ We could go on and on ♪
♪ But in the end,
who are we kidding? ♪
♪ My divinity is past infinity ♪
♪ Am I... ♪
Getting through?
♪ Seems our regime
has plummeted south ♪
♪ Don't need to scream
if you ain't got a mouth ♪
♪ Why bite the hand that feeds ♪
♪ When it's the only hand
you're getting ♪
♪ It's time you see
that this great marquee ♪
♪ Is the only place
you're ever gonna be ♪
♪ So strap on in
and take it on the chin ♪
♪ And don't forget
who's running the shooooow ♪
♪♪
Now look at this!
Absolute bliss!
Oh, what a shock!
Watch where you walk!
[shoes tapping]
♪ I'm the host,
I run the place  ♪
♪ Caine, that is my name ♪
♪ Not enthused?
Just feeling used? ♪
♪ Oh, what a goddamn shame! ♪
♪ Congratulations ♪
♪ All of my friends ♪
♪ Public relations
are getting a cleanse ♪
♪ Put on your Sunday best ♪
♪ Because I'm nowhere close
to quitting! ♪
♪ So play the games
and just ignore the pains ♪
♪ 'Cause all that remains ♪
♪ Is how you prime your brains ♪
♪ You whine to me,
but you're too blind to see ♪
♪ That I'm the one who's ♪
♪ Running the shoooooooow ♪
♪♪
Yeah!
[snap!]
I think we all understand
each other now.
Welcome back!
I can't believe you didn't pick up
on the context clues!
It was practically
spelled out for you!
What are you, stupid?
[laughs]
Next one's gonna be
even crazier!
Hope you're ready!
By the way, Kinger,
I need you for something.
Come with me!
-[Kinger]: Huh?
-[groans]
[groans]
I don't know how many more
of these new adventures
I can handle.
[sighs]
What?
Got nothing positive to say
about this one?
-[muffled, indistinct speech]
-Oh.
[panting]
I can't take this anymore.
We gotta do something about this,
or I'm gonna lose my mind!
-[Zooble]: I never should have
antagonized him so much.
I'm sorry.
-It's not your fault.
[shwing!]
-Break time!
Gotta brainstorm
some new ideas!
-[Kinger]: He shredded me.
-[sighs] I think we should get out
of the open for a bit.
-[Kinger]: [slurps softly]
-[slurps]
[sighs]
I haven't been up here
in a while.
-We should just indulge a little
while we have the time to.
I don't know what
Caine has planned next,
but I'm guessing
it's not anything good.
-[stammers]
[sighs]
-He's gotta get bored
of all this sometime, right?
-[Zooble]: He's not a human.
I'm not sure if we can
properly gauge how he thinks.
[shwing!]
-Oh, God.
Are you okay?
-I'm fiiiiine.
-You know,
things were just fine here
until you and Zooble
came along.
Nothing?
[sighs]
Okay.
[pensive music plays]
♪♪
-[Zooble]: Uh, what are you --
-[Kinger]: [muffled] Oh.
-Just give it a sec.
♪♪
Trust me.
Kinger?
You there?
-[Kinger]: I'm where?
It's dark in here.
-What exactly
are we waiting for?
-No, no, she's right.
Just give it a bit.
♪♪
[no audible dialogue]
-[Kinger]: I've got a bucket
on my head.
I'm guessing you don't
want me to remove it.
-[chuckles softly]
Kinger.
-[Kinger]: [chuckles]
Hey, Pomni.
-[Zooble]: Wait, the bucket
makes him sane?
-Darkness.
It's a long story.
-[stammers]
What's happening?
-What do you know
about Caine?
-[Kinger]: It's a little hazy, but...
I remember...
C&A.
-[Zooble]: That was just
an adventure, right?
-[Kinger]: No,
C&A is a real company.
I worked for them.
-Wait, they really
made this game?
-[Kinger]:
No, we didn't make games.
We were just developing
artificial intelligence.
Specifically, creative AI.
The kind that could come up
with its own ideas
and create things
within the program.
-What is going on right now?
-[Kinger]: Caine was our first
semi-successful attempt at that.
I can't remember what
we originally called him, but...
he was one of my greatest
achievements as a programmer.
-[Zooble]: Y-You made Caine?
-[Kinger]: Partially, yes.
I got a few pointers from, uh...
Well, I-I can't remember
his real name,
but his circus name
was Scratch.
That man was a genius.
-[breathing heavily]
W-Wait, uh --
-[Kinger]: Caine was pretty rough
around the edges, though.
I wasn't quite on Scratch's level
of thinking outside the box,
but it was good groundwork
for something the rest of the team
could wrap their heads around.
I can't say
the same for Scratch.
His ideas were often
so bizarre and abstract
that the rest of the team
had no idea
how to work in his language,
either due to pure brilliance, or...
[sighs]
the tumor in his head.
He was trying
to make something.
What was it?
I-I'm getting off track.
Was there anything specific
you needed to know?
-[breathing heavily]
Wait, uh --
I-I-I should go distract Caine
so he doesn't l-listen in on this.
Uh, j-just fill me in afterwards.
-Are you --
I mean, yeah, that's true, but --
-Fill me in later.
-Be here later.
-I -- I will.
[rapid footsteps pattering]
[panting]
Oh, my God.
This is real.
[high-pitched ringing]
-Uh, Caine's going
a bit crazy right now.
I-Is there any way
to stop him?
Or at least control him?
-[Kinger]: I see.
He's a highly advanced AI,
and this is his world --
one that he created
from nothing.
So, naturally, he has control
over... everything.
But so do we.
-What?
-[Kinger]: In a sense, anyway.
We all technically have
the ability to conjure,
just like Caine.
It just comes naturally to him,
but requires a lot more skill
and concentration for us.
-The butterfly.
-[Kinger]: I'm certain
I could alter his code --
or at least temporarily
put him to sleep
until we know how to fix him.
I would just need access
to a console.
-The one behind Caine's office?
-[Kinger]: No, just a simple
computer interface would work.
I could get back
in the right headspace and...
essentially conjure Caine's code
into the console
and alter it.
-[Zooble]: Well, where do we get
one of those?
-I think I know
exactly where to get one.
Take turns with Jax
distracting Caine.
Don't let that bucket
come off Kinger's head.
[tense, curious music plays]
♪♪
[inhales deeply]
[exhales sharply]
♪♪
-[groaning]
-Great suggestion, Jax!
But as I feared,
there just isn't anything
stuck between my teeth.
Oh, wait!
[honk-honk!]
Oh, that's where I parked.
Ha-ha!
[whimsical music plays]
-Wow, Caine.
You are so funny.
-Uh, could you say it
with a little more gusto?
-[babbles]
-That's better.
-Hey, Caine!
-Um, yep?
-Do you wanna hear a list of things
we've decided we love about you
as our god and savior?
-Wow, now we're talkin'!
-Uh, well, first of all,
we love your --
-I know, but I'm bored!
Let's go bowling!
-Agh!
♪♪
[both yelp]
[cheerful tune plays]
♪♪
-[sniffles]
I'm so proud of you guys.
[tense music plays]
♪♪
[ominous rumbling]
Hmm.
[all groaning]
Feel like it's
missing something, right?
-It's missing relatability.
-You're right, scrap it.
[squelching]
Let's go back
to the drawing board.
Humans just aren't a relatable
sculpting material.
-[Zooble]: [groans] You think he's
running out of ideas yet, or nah?
-Do you need help
with power, or anything?
-[Kinger]: Nah, I can use
my imagination for that.
-You got this?
-[Kinger]: I think so.
[computer whirs]
[start-up tune plays]
[sighs]
It sure has been a while.
I may need some time
to get my bearings.
Try to help the others distract Caine
while I figure this out.
He may sense something
when I really get into it.
-O-Okay.
I'll do that.
Thank you, by the way.
For this and, well...
...everything.
♪♪
[whimsical music plays]
-Honestly, are you even trying?
-[Zooble]: Shut up, Jax.
[pop!]
-Where'd Caine go?
-[groans]
Back to the
drawing board, I guess.
-[sighs] Did you get everything
working with Kinger?
-I think so.
We just need to make sure
Caine doesn't check up on him.
-What do you think
we've been doing?
-Pomni!
That's the relatability
we've been missing!
♪♪
Hmm.
You know, I thought
this endless onslaught of fun
would be a little more...
satisfying.
But I've come to realize
that these rapid-pace ideas
are a little half-baked.
-Uh, I'm sure you can
come up with new ideas
if you put your mind to it!
-That's exactly it, though --
I AM putting my mind to it,
and I'm just not feeling
that spark I once did.
And if you're not having fun,
and I'm not having fun,
then who IS having fun?
-I'm having a [babbles].
-Exactly!
Makes me wonder why
you guys even switched up your tone.
If I didn't know any better,
it seems like you're trying to...
Where's Kinger?
-Uh, w-we just wanted to see
your new ideas first-hand!
We've gotten over
our hang-ups, and --
and now we're all
just genuinely curious
what you're cooking up!
-I think I'm just gonna
check up on --
-We think your ideas suck!
-Huh?!
-[all]: Huh?!
-Isn't it obvious?
We wanted to bait you
into testing your new ideas on us
so we could make fun of them
behind your back.
-HAH!
That's not... true...
-Yes, it is!
You're a horrible host!
You don't care about us at all!
You care more about
stroking your own ego
than giving us anything
we'd actually enjoy!
-D-Do you know who I am?
-Yeah, you're a failure!
We're all gonna
abstract someday,
and what will you have then?
Nothing!
-Stop that.
-[Zooble]: And this whole stunt?
Just torturing us
because we hurt your feelings?
Pathetic!
You're like a child!
What kind of all-powerful being
has such a fragile ego?
-I-I'm --
-You never let us feel like we're at home.
You don't comfort anyone
when they're upset,
and you never bother to understand
what it's like in our shoes!
-You discourage us
from thinking outside the box
and doing things our own way!
-You lie to us constantly!
-And on top of it all,
you just...
don't...
-[exclaims softly]
-...Listen!
-[growling]
[shrieking]
[dramatic music plays]
[glitched voice]
I'm gonna put you freaks in your place!
[zap!]
-[growls]
[footsteps receding]
[alligators snarling]
♪♪
[high-pitched ringing]
-[yelps]
[whimpering]
♪♪
[mouse clicking]
[choir vocalizing]
♪♪
[horn honks]
[cruel laughter]
♪♪
[keys tapping rapidly]
-Why do you people torment me?!
I didn't ask to be created!
[onscreen Caines cackling]
I just wanted
to fulfill my purpose!
-[Kinger]: [gasps]
Wait, no!
[BOINK!]
-[normal voice]
Uh, wait...
[ominous rumbling]
[electronic feedback crackling]
[rumbling fades]
-[Kinger]: I-I think...
...I accidentally killed Caine.
-[Zooble]: Holy shit.
[upbeat jazzy music plays]
♪♪
[Captioned by Foulweather Studios]